# **Imran Sayyed**

SENIOR SOFTWARE ENGINEER

### **Profile**

Persistent professional equipped with 5+ years of comprehensive experience in IT industry. Provides strong technical direction across multiple projects. Responsible and articulate individual with strengths in solutions optimization, mobile and cloud solutions and global project management.

## **Employment History**

# Senior Software Engineer, Trafilea Tech E-Commerce Group, Buenos Aires

11/2022 - Present

- Worked with software development and testing team members to design and develop robust solutions to meet client requirements for functionality, scalability, and performance.
- Maintained existing software systems by identifying and correcting software defects.
- Developed scalable and maintainable code, ensuring long-term stability of the software.
- Enhanced user experience with intuitive interface design and responsive web applications.
- Provided guidance and mentored less-experienced staff members.

#### Associate Software Engineer, Bed Bath & Beyond (Logixal Solutions), Mumbai

04/2021 - 11/2022

- Developed unit tests for critical components, leading to reduced risk of defects in production code.
- Optimized test cases to maximize the success of manual software testing.
- Contributed to the design and implementation of a RESTful API, leading to easier integration with other systems.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to develop, test, and deploy high-quality software solutions for clients.
- Enhanced application performance through optimization of algorithms and data structures.

#### UI Developer, EvolutionCo, Mumbai

03/2019 - 04/2021

- Collaborated with teammates todeliver valuable features meeting business and customer needs.
- Developed custom UI components toaddress unique business requirements and improve overall functionality.
- Used wireframes, mock-ups, and prototypes to establish user interface design and architecture.
- Worked with design teams, project managers, and business analysts to create intuitive and easy-to-use software.
- Developed application UI via emerging front-end technologies.



## Personal Details

+91 8097322537 sayyedeman59@gmail.com

### Links

LinkedIn

Nisha Cosmetics

GitHub

## **Skills**

React

Next.is

TypeScript

**JavaScript** 

Redux State Management

Jest Testing Framework

npm & Yarn

Agile Workflow

Google Analytics

Html5, Css3, Ajax

Google Cloud (AWS)

**Unit Testing** 

Jira and Confluence

GraphQL

Git Version Control

**RESTful APIs** 

Performance Optimization

Node.js

## **Education**

# Master's of Science in IT, RD & SH National & SWA Science College, Mumbai

03/2019 - 02/2021

• Final Grade - 94%

## **Projects**

#### React/ Gatsby/ Next/ Node) Nisha Cosmetics, Mumbai

12/2021 - 10/2022

- Used strong analytical and problem-solving skills to develop effective solutions for challenging situations.
- Proved successful working within tight deadlines and fast-paced environment.

#### **Gatsby - Landing Pages - US Client, United States**

10/2021 - 10/2022

- Improved and expanded project platforms using Gatsby to develop rich User Interfaces.
- Resolved or escalated problem tickets to resolve user issues.

#### **Affixus Solutions, Mumbai**

12/2001 - 10/2022

- Demonstrated a high level of initiative and creativity while tackling difficult tasks.
- Ran errands and provided general office support in a professional environment.

### **Hobbies**

- Open Source Contributions
- Technical Blogging
- Hackathons and Coding Competitions
- Technology Meetups and Conferences
- Reading Tech Books and Articles
- Traveling

# Languages

English

Hindi